

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER DEVOFS ENGINEER MICROSOFT AZ

20F South Sinthi Road, Kolkata, 700050, India

□ (+91) 98-3642-4746 | 🗷 pritibhunia3004@outlook.com | 🖸 pritibhunia | 🛅 pritibhunia | 🐚 pritibhunia

# **Summary**

Software Developer and certified Azure DevOps Engineer working with Siemens Healthineers, having 5 years experience with cloud services implementation, infrastructure and application deployment automation, CI/CD pipeline implementation for infrastructure and application deployment. Skilled in C#, .NET, PowerShell Scripting and other DevOps tools like Ansible, Git for implementing deployment automation, backend development, writing automation tests. Experienced with Kusto Query Language to implement monitoring solutions using Azure Application Insights and Azure OMS Suite. Exposure to Hybrid cloud, Google Cloud Platform and AWS Cloud too.

## **Education**

#### St. Thomas' College of Engineering and Technology

Kolkata, India

B.Tech. IN Electronics and Communication Engineering

Aug. 2012 - Jul. 2016

- Graduated with a Bachelor of Technology in Electronics and Communication Engineering, securing an overall GPA of 8.77/10
- Technical core committee member of SREY(Tech fest of STCET)

# **Work Experience**

#### Siemens Healthineers India LLP

Bangalore, India

SENIOR ENGINEER - DESIGN & DEVELOPMENT

May, 2021 - Present

- Software Developer, responsible for multiple successful delivery of a diagnostic imaging based digital healthcare product teamplay.
- Responsible for requirement gathering, successful development and delivery of different components of teamplay, end-to-end pipeline creation for infrastructure and application deployment, with 80% accuracy.
- Responsible for enhancements, leading to successful development of several features including but not limited to Edge platform management and installation, GitOps integration, proxy setup, monitoring services integration and creation of new version of the product.
- Responsible for writing automation test cases using XUnit, BDD, TDD framework, Integration testing and Goss testing.
- Tech Stack: C#, .NET 5, Kubernetes, Azure, DevOps, Ansible, PowerShell, GitOps

#### **EY Global Delivery Services India LLP**

Bangalore, India

DEVOPS ENGINEER

Sep, 2019 - Apr, 2021

- Worked with multiple clients as DevOps Engineer for requirement gathering and decision-making regarding the Architecture Diagram.
- Provisioned easily manageable cloud infrastructures using multiple Azure IaaS and PaaS services for multiple projects in Azure utilizing Infrastructure as Code(IaC) tools like Ansible, Azure DevOps depending on the application requirements.
- Built fully automated CI/CD pipelines on Azure DevOps for containerized applications using Azure Kubernetes Service and Azure Container Registry with 95% efficiency.
- Automated compliance report generation process using Azure DevOps, PowerShell script and ARM template.
- Configured performance dashboards and alerts for monitoring the applications using Kusto Query Language, Application Insights, Log Analytics.
- Responsible for automating the new client on-boarding process for the products which saved around one week time and workforce requirements with 90% accuracy.
- Tech Stack: Azure, Azure DevOps, PowerShell, YAML, ARM template, Kubernetes, Kusto Query Languange, SQL, Java

## Cognizant Chennai & Kolkata, India

CLOUD ENGINEER

Jul. 2016 - Sep. 2019

- · Worked with one of the Insurance client for requirement gathering and decision-making about the on-boarding the APIs and security prospect.
- Responsible for configuring the APIs from both Cloud and On-Premises in Azure API Management, designed the developer portal for external consumers and worked on Application Insights to set up custom alerts and customer dashboards using Kusto Query Language.
- Responsible for automating report generation and on-boarding flow using PowerShell script. Worked on multiple POC to improve the process, API Management migration and additional component deployment for the existing infrastructure.
- Provisioned easily manageable cloud infrastructures for one of the Healthcare client and Hackathon event in Azure using ARM template single click deployment utilizing various IaaS and PaaS services focusing on high-availability, fault tolerance, disaster recovery and auto-scaling.
- Responsible for automating the MFA solution for RDS along with full infrastructure deployment in Azure for one of the Healthcare client.
- Tech Stack: Azure, PowerShell, ARM template, Kusto Query Languange, SQL, XML, C#



**DevOps** Azure, Kubernetes, Docker, ARM template, Bash Scripting, PowerShell Scripting, Kusto Query Language

**Databases** Azure SQL, MySQL

Programming Core Java, C#, .NET 5, Python
Frontend HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript

**Tools** Git, Jira, Azure DevOps, Ansible

**Industry knowledge** Cloud Computing, Deployment Automation, Continuous Integration, Monitoring & Analytics

Application Insights, Log Analytics, Azure ARC, API Management, Azure Kubernetes Services, Container Registries,

Virtual Machines & VM Scale Sets, Virtual Networks, Load Balancer, Traffic Manager & Application Gateways,

Azure Cloud Services

Azure Cloud Services

Backup and Recovery Solutions, High Availability, Web Application Deployments & Custom Domain Configurations,

Storage solutions, Key Vault, SQL Servers & Databases, Data Factory, Logic Apps, Azure Identity.

**Languages** English, Hindi, Bengali

## **Certifications**

• Microsoft Certified: DevOps Engineer Expert, 2020

• Microsoft Certified: Azure Administrator Associate, 2020

• AZ-303 Microsoft Azure Architect Technologies, 2021

# **Extracurricular Activity**

- Volunteering for social and cultural events which engage the associates in the areas of community welfare and environment.
- Learning new tech stack and building a portfolio.
- Reading, writing, playing guitar, dancing and working out almost regularly, time permit.